<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on Something Like Games</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on Something Like Games</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Networking tutorial 2: The "walking skeleton"</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-2-walking-skeleton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-2-walking-skeleton/</guid><description>Ich habe wirklich lange über die &lt;em>richtige&lt;/em> Vorgehensweise für dieses Tutorial nachgedacht. Schließlich gibt es verschiedene Möglichkeiten, wenn man, wie hier, die aktuell geplanten vier Komponenten entwickeln möchte. Ein Extremfall wäre es, pro Tutorial jeweils eine Komponente vollständig zu entwickeln und dadurch erst zum Schluss die Kommunikation zwischen den Komponenten zu ermöglichen. Ich habe mich für eine andere Variante entschieden und setze alle Komponenten direkt ohne wirkliche Funktionalität auf, um sie anschließend in jedem Tutorial, passend zum Thema, mit weiteren Inhalten zu füllen.</description></item><item><title>Networking tutorial 1: General information and overview</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-1-overview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-1-overview/</guid><description>Godot 4 is on its way to the first release candidate. The difference between Godot 3.x and Godot 4 is huge. While there are already various tutorials on many of the changes, it seems to me that the area of network programming has been neglected and that although, or maybe because, there have been a lot of changes there as well. In addition, I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in this part, because so far almost only pure multiplayer games have managed to fascinate me for a long time and I can use my professional experience in this area.</description></item></channel></rss>