<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Godot Engine on Something Like Games</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/tags/godot-engine/</link><description>Recent content in Godot Engine on Something Like Games</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 11:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/tags/godot-engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Netzwerktutorial 4: Login 2 - Gateway and Authentication Server</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-4-login-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 11:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-4-login-2/</guid><description>The source code for this tutorial series can be found in this GitHub repository. The following list shows all articles of this series published so far:
Networking tutorial 1: General information and overview Networking tutorial 2: The &amp;#34;walking skeleton&amp;#34; Networking tutorial 3: Login 1 - The game client Netzwerktutorial 4: Login 2 - Gateway and Authentication Server In the last article we created the game client to the point where it wants to contact the gateway server with login data.</description></item><item><title>Networking tutorial 3: Login 1 - The game client</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-3-login-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-3-login-1/</guid><description>With the help of the last article, we now have a basic framework consisting of three servers running on UDP ports &lt;code>1909&lt;/code>-&lt;code>1911&lt;/code> and informing us via console output about connection establishment/disconnection of clients. This article deals with the first part of our login process and we create the game client to the point where it connects to the gateway server and sends the login data there. But before that we will discuss a bit more generally the login process and RPCs in Godot.</description></item><item><title>Networking tutorial 2: The "walking skeleton"</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-2-walking-skeleton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-2-walking-skeleton/</guid><description>Ich habe wirklich lange über die &lt;em>richtige&lt;/em> Vorgehensweise für dieses Tutorial nachgedacht. Schließlich gibt es verschiedene Möglichkeiten, wenn man, wie hier, die aktuell geplanten vier Komponenten entwickeln möchte. Ein Extremfall wäre es, pro Tutorial jeweils eine Komponente vollständig zu entwickeln und dadurch erst zum Schluss die Kommunikation zwischen den Komponenten zu ermöglichen. Ich habe mich für eine andere Variante entschieden und setze alle Komponenten direkt ohne wirkliche Funktionalität auf, um sie anschließend in jedem Tutorial, passend zum Thema, mit weiteren Inhalten zu füllen.</description></item><item><title>Networking tutorial 1: General information and overview</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-1-overview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/network-tutorial-1-overview/</guid><description>Godot 4 is on its way to the first release candidate. The difference between Godot 3.x and Godot 4 is huge. While there are already various tutorials on many of the changes, it seems to me that the area of network programming has been neglected and that although, or maybe because, there have been a lot of changes there as well. In addition, I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in this part, because so far almost only pure multiplayer games have managed to fascinate me for a long time and I can use my professional experience in this area.</description></item><item><title>Is Godot 4 ready for AA- or even AAA?</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/status-of-godot-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 11:30:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/status-of-godot-4/</guid><description>Shortly after I posted my last article, Juan Linietsky, one of the founders of Godot Engine, published an article about the competitiveness of Godot Engine in AA and AAA game development.
The article is really worth reading, because on the one hand he goes into the technical possibilities with Godot 4 (renderer, physics, scripting, GDExtension, &amp;hellip;) and on the other hand he points out what he thinks is still missing to develop AA/AAA level games with the Godot Engine.</description></item><item><title>Why I chose Godot Engine</title><link>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/why-i-chose-godot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 18:56:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.somethinglikegames.de/en/blog/2023/why-i-chose-godot/</guid><description>If you want to deal with game development in this day and age, you are confronted with a luxury problem right from the start. While in the early days of video game development, the sound and graphics output used for almost every game was developed or reworked in-house, nowadays you can choose from a variety of possible tools.
I have &amp;ldquo;published&amp;rdquo; two computer games so far.
The first game was a 2D jump&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;run that told the story of my (now) wife and me, which we used as wedding invitations.</description></item></channel></rss>